<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Forensics on blog.davsk.com</title>
    <link>http://localhost:8080/forensic/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Forensics on blog.davsk.com</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>2012 © davsk.com</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2015 08:50:20 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:8080/forensic/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>warrantee</title>
      <link>http://localhost:8080/forensic/warrantee/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2015 08:50:20 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:8080/forensic/warrantee/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h4 id=&#34;use-hd-video-camera-to-create-compelling-evidence:897ae129ccbea17062489d8022720c5e&#34;&gt;Use HD video camera to create compelling evidence&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A warrantee claim for a problem that is intermittent can be a difficult thing to prove.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The solution was to use a video camera to document the intermittent problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One look and the 60 seconds of video extracted from almost an hour was enough to get repairs&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>custody</title>
      <link>http://localhost:8080/forensic/custody/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2015 08:50:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:8080/forensic/custody/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h4 id=&#34;video-editing-to-present-key-evidence-easily:9a22cb53df2358d28d698cdb3c9f26fd&#34;&gt;Video editing to present key evidence easily.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The custodial parent was watching an R rate movie in the presence of minor children.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was asked to work with the psychology expert to develop some evidentiary exhibits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was able to take the rental version of the movie, rip it into a file that I could edit, splice excerpts of the selected scenes together into a 5 minute movie. I was also able to provide a half dozen screen shots on 8x10 photo paper.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>divorce</title>
      <link>http://localhost:8080/forensic/divorce/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2015 08:49:35 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:8080/forensic/divorce/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h4 id=&#34;use-the-computer-to-do-your-job-quicker-easier-and-better:48a03e2856b1506f820a3ff28e3666e6&#34;&gt;Use the computer to do your job quicker, easier, and better.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The discovery in this case was over 2000 pages of financial information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We set up a laptop computer and scanner in the library of the opposing counsel and a few hours later, all of the documents had been scanned into the computer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By the following morning, the documents had been OCRed, indexed, and place on CD.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By the following Monday, the documents had been identified and a missing documents list had been prepared.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The resulting CD was then used to distribute information to financial experts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>assault</title>
      <link>http://localhost:8080/forensic/assault/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2015 08:49:05 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:8080/forensic/assault/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h4 id=&#34;scaled-computer-modeling-to-set-the-scene:bd687e1ea1391a00ebc4c72d32705509&#34;&gt;Scaled computer modeling to set the scene&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A request was made for an illustrative exhibit, a jail house door complete with cuff port.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I take a picture of the door and make some measurements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I prepared a drawing of the door using a CAD program listing all of the dimensions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I then built the lightweight wooden jailhouse door as a representational illustrative exhibit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The door was then delivered to the court house on the day of trial for use by the defense attorney.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>rape</title>
      <link>http://localhost:8080/forensic/rape/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2015 08:48:36 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:8080/forensic/rape/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h3 id=&#34;computer-forensic-tools-cannot-reveal-what-is-not-there-and-cannot-conceal-what-is-there:211ea848a43bf1477c6a04bbeae03335&#34;&gt;Computer forensic tools cannot reveal what is not there and cannot conceal what is there.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The evidence provided consisted of duplicates of two hard disk drives, one from a laptop and one from a desktop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first step was to verify the digital signature of the discovery. Instead we determined that the evidence had been altered while in police custody.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next step was to recover and identify files on the hard disk drives. The file information was transferred to a database and filtered using simple sql commands to identify potentially troublesome files and to explain why certain files were not relevant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had to testify in this case that the hard disk drive had been altered while in police custody and on cross examination I explained that the access time on a particular file selected by the prosecutor indicated that it had not been accessed or viewed on that computer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>murder</title>
      <link>http://localhost:8080/forensic/murder/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2015 08:48:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:8080/forensic/murder/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h4 id=&#34;using-computer-graphics-to-tell-the-story:2ea5b58990a4ea9bf957e359fae9bad0&#34;&gt;Using computer graphics to tell the story.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The young drug addict had been accused of shooting his unlicensed pharmaceutical dealer in the back of the head with a .38 Special while testing his wares.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He claimed it was an accident, must have been a ricochet when he tripped and fell with the pistol they had been target shooting with while drunk and stoned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My job was to convert the 5/16” in the coroner’s report to a decimal format and compare it with the .357” in the ballistics report.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next problem was to present the information in the most effective way. I used a copy of the photograph of the hole in the skull to place concentric overlays of different diameters. I also created a clear film overlay with a typical picture of a bullet before and after impact . Placing the overlay over the copy of the picture allows for a direct comparison of relative size of the bullet, the hole, and the coroner’s report.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The result of the exhibit is documented in the newspaper article on the  LawAdvocateOnline.com website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>